本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： HTC YYlwj0611 带着猫咪私奔
校对： 海之南   后期： 海之南
舞蹈学院 前情提要
Previously on Dance Academy...
杰弗里先生把自己欣赏的演员列了个表
Sir Jeffery has a list of who fits his vision.
从你们进校第一天起他就开始列了
He starts it when you enter first year
随后他会根据受伤情况或体型变化而不断修正
Then he revises it for injury or change of body shape.
够了
That's enough.
她没事的 我老师以前一直这么训练我
She's fine. My teachers did that to me all the time.
我成功请回了舞团曾经的头牌舞者之一
I have managed to lure back one of the company's leading lights.
我受够了 我一直在想 这一切何时才能结束
I'm sick of it! I keep thinking, when is this going to stop?
因为我好想摆脱你
Because I want so much to be rid of you.
舞蹈学院 第三季第11集
我们已经到了一年之末
We're definitely reaching the pointy end of the year.
每个人都感觉到了
Everyone is feeling that.
改变 无处不在
Change. It's, like, lurking everywhere.
我是说 我觉得我们应该在一起
I said, I think we should be together.
是的 我听出你的意思了
Yeah, I got that part.
为什么呢
Why?
你对我说过
You told me once.
我得有一个长远的追求 我现在找到了
I have to figure out what I wanted long-term, and I did.
有两件事
Two things.
其一是我会竭尽所能进入舞团
I'm going to do everything I can to get into the company,
其二就是和你在一起
and I want to be with you.
克里斯提 塔拉 你们得过来看看这个
Christian, Tara, you guys need to see this.
考虑一下吧
Think it over.
担任了国家芭蕾舞团艺术指导十六年
After 16 years as artistic director
并在剧院奉献了毕生精力之后
of the National Ballet and a lifetime in the theatre,
我想是时候完美谢幕了
I feel the day has come to exit the stage gracefully.
- 哇哦 - 游戏规则看来要改变了
- Whoa. - Game changer.
我将把我在舞团的话语权
I do leave assured my legacy will be in safe hands
转交给新一任的艺术指导
under the new artistic director,
我的得意门生 瑞贝卡・布莱斯怀特
my gifted protegee, Rebecca Braithwaite.
在上任初期 这位新艺术指导
At this early stage the new artistic director
拒绝透露她对于舞团的个人展望
refused to be drawn on her personal vision for the company.
这事儿有意思了
Things just got interesting.
评论家称其过于年轻
Critics may claim she's too young,
对此职务也显得经验不足
too inexperienced for this appointment.
然而这却会对舞团传统带来一次变革
However, It does suggest there is a push away from tradition.
可以确定的是
One thing is certain
芭蕾舞界将会迎来一个活跃的崭新时代
the ballet community faces a tumultuous new era.
是我 我演斯瓦希尔德
I got it! I'm Swanhilde!
奥利演麦克白
Ollie Macbeth.
本和克里斯提 你们都饰演白马王子
Ben and Christian, you'll both be dancing Prince Charming.
塔拉 你饰演火鸟
Tara, you'll be doing Firebird.
我为你预约了威克斯医生
I'm making you an appointment to see Dr Wicks.
然后是阿比盖尔
And Abigail...
抱歉 你怎么能在我们不知道瑞贝卡有何要求的情况下
Sorry, how can you assign our final audition solos
为我们安排最终试演的独舞节目呢
when we don't know what Rebecca is looking for?
你不能指望靠一直涂精油来治好你的背
You can't keep applying heat cream and hope it magically fixes itself.
我对她的要求是只能低强度运动
I'm putting her on low-impact,
不能做阿拉贝斯克舞姿和快速的舞蹈动作
no arabesques, no allegro.
阿拉贝斯克舞姿 单腿直立 一臂前伸 另一腿往后抬起 另一臂舒展扬起
但试演不到三周就要开始了
But auditions are less than three weeks away.
只是肌肉问题 我不会受伤的
It's just muscular. I'm not doing damage.
难道你要等到受伤了才罢休
Don't you love it when they get their medical degrees?
如果你从去年的事中吸取哪怕一点点的教训
If you've gained a skerrick of sense since last year,
你就应该听威克斯医生的话
you'll listen to Dr Wicks.
又来了
Again?
一 二 三
One, two, three.
去问问杰弗里先生的名单是否还在
Go ask if Sir Jeffery's list went with him.
我还以为你已经迫不及待地上网查过了
I would have thought you'd be desperate to do some networking.
还没人能通过跳麦克白的独舞进舞团的
No-one's ever gotten into the company dancing a Macbeth solo.
这是事实 也是诅咒
It's fact, it's cursed.
幸好我还有别的选择
It's a good thing I've got another option, then.
恭喜你获得了火鸟的角色 你的最爱之一 是吗
Congratulations on Firebird. One of your favourites, right?
你知道我没理由相信什么克里斯提会改头换面这种事吧
Do you realized I have no reason to trust this born-again Christian thing?
- 没错 - 你不能靠"考虑一下吧"这种话
- Good line. - You can't say what you said
就把过去一笔勾销
like it cancels out everything and go, 'Think it over.'
你要我怎么接受这种事
How do I have head space for that?
说得对 你应该把精力集中在试演上
You're right. You should focus on auditions
这样我就能向你证明我有所改变了
while I prove to you I'm stepping up.
很高兴能听到你这么说 里德同学 过会儿来找我
Thrilled to hear it, Mr Reed. Come and find me later.
疏散工作做得不错 消防管理员向你致敬
Nice evacuation things. Your fire warden salutes you.
相较于杰弗里先生
Compared to Sir Jeffery,
你的审美观念是什么样的呢
how would you describe your aesthetic,
毫无疑问更现代 对吗
more contemporary, surely?
我的审美很简单
My aesthetic is simple.
我想要全世界最出色的舞者 无论来自哪里
I want the best dancers on the planet, wherever they come from.
失陪
Excuse me.
璐璐 在某些特殊情况下 速度比形式更重要
Lulu, in certain situations, speed is more important than form.
六 七 八
Six, seven, eight!
一 二 三 四 五 六
One, two, three, four, five, six,
七 八 一 二 三 四
seven, eight. And one, two, three, four,
五 六 七 八
five, six, seven, eight.
一 二 三
And one, two, three,
四 五 六 七 八
four, five, six, seven, eight.
一 二 三 四
And one, two, three, four...
各位潜在的备选舞者 我向你们致敬
Potential backup dancers, I salute you.
谢谢你们没让我丢脸
Thanks for not embarrassing me.
我们今晚通知复试的事
We'll be in contact tonight about call-back,
所以不管做什么事 都别忘了带手机
so whatever you do, don't drop your phone in your coffee.
嘿 我想说我是你的超级粉丝
Hey, I just want to say, huge fan.
噢 谢谢
Oh, cheers.
米卡才是最棒的 她跳的时候想不好看都难
Meeka's the best. It's hard not to look good doing a chory.
是的 她同意参加我的巡演时我有点受宠若惊
I know. I'm slightly terrified she agreed to do my tour.
我其实是说你的音乐
But I actually meant your music.
我做普拉提时一直听你的歌
You're all over my Pilates playlist.
我貌似把你的网站地址发给了杰西来给她创作灵感
I may have sent Jess the link to your web channel for inspiration.
太疯狂了 你可是杰西卡・麦尔白
That's crazy.I mean, You're Jessica Mauboy,
我这是废话
which you obviously know.
这是否意味着我有复试的机会了
Does this mean I get a call-back?
备选演员的复试 我觉得目标可以再高一些
For backup dancing? I think we could aim higher.
学年结束时你的奖学金也将停止发放
The end of the school year also means the end of your scholarship.
- 你考虑过怎么赚取生活花销吗 - 当然
- Have you thought about how you'll cover living expenses? - Absolutely.
我打算和国家芭蕾舞团签约
I plan on getting a contract with the National Ballet Company.
你可能听说过我的计划
You might have heard of it.
希望你能实现
I hope you do.
但如果你没能如愿 最终巡演将会花费不少钱
If that doesn't eventuate, the audition circuit is expensive,
- 尤其是当你需要出国的时候 - 是的 当然
- particularly if you need to head overseas. - Right, of course.
我为你找了些可以申请的补助金
I found some grants you might be eligible for.
我不需要 我能找到一份工作的
I don't need them. I can get a job.
我本该今年就去工作挣钱的
I should have been working this year, saving up.
没人说要把你赶走
No-one is suggesting we throw you out.
非常感谢 但你们为我做得够多的了
I appreciate that, but you guys have done enough.
二 滑步 击足跳
Two. Glissade, cabriole.
蓄力
Gather for force.
爆发
Explode!
你们慢了 跟上
You're behind the music. Come on.
克里斯提 继续
Christian, keep up.
本杰明
Benjamin!
我有个计划
I have a plan.
这边走
Come this way.
我们需要安排多少次
How many of my unique
单独授课
private coaching sessions shall we pencil in?
我要自己完成这套舞蹈
I'm going to work through this one on my own.
你和本都演白马王子 是我的主意
You and Ben both doing Prince Charming, that was my call.
要是有其他合适的方式 我可以帮你争取一个
Either suits you a different way, I can help you find a unique take.
这段独舞我没问题的
I'm good with the solo.
你不可能永远在我身边手把手指导吧
You're not going to be around forever to hold my hand.
交给我了
I've got this one.
看看赛斯吉娅
Look at Saskia.
干嘛
Why?
这是不是她折了脚踝那晚上呀
Oh! Is this the night she broke her ankle?
要是不让我排练 我要怎么达到这水准
How am I supposed to match that if I'm not allowed to rehearse?
年度压轴大戏的主角
Lead role in the end-of-year production!
选角机会千载难逢
The casting coup of the ages!
拜托啦孩子们 别拐弯抹角了 你们有啥别有用心
Children, please. Can we just get to the ulterior motive?
全国各地的准毕业生们
School leavers around the country
都纵情于毕业恶作剧
are indulging in graduation pranks.
三年级学生禁止做这种蠢事
Third-years are banned from such tomfoolery.
尽管冒着取消试镜资格的险
On pain of being excluded from auditions.
但作为一个二年级学生
However, being a second-year...
我有豁免惩罚的权利哦
I'm exempt from such punishment.
你就是最佳恶作剧代言人啦
You are the perfect pranker-by-proxy.
这就是你们正热衷的事情吗
This is what is occupying your attention,
不该是新艺术指导吗
not the new artistic director?
这可是咱们的毕业仪式 怎么能不找点乐子
It's a rite of passage. The fun shouldn't have to die.
本杰明 我真抱歉 我不能冒险惹雷恩老师生气
Benjamin, I'm sorry, but I can't risk Raine wrath.
那就算你同意啦
So that's a yes?
奥利弗 绝对不行
Oliver, it's a very firm no.
我和韦斯做了调查 知道吗 瑞贝卡有人体运动学博士学位
Wes and I are researching. Do you know Rebecca has a PhD in kinesiology?
她可真是名副其实的舞蹈医生
She's literally a dance doctor.
韦斯 你能不能劝劝她就花一小时
Wes, can you tell her that she can spend an hour
在一场试镜中支援我演唱 就一首歌
to backup sing in one audition. One song.
这完全没意义 你当然不会为了某个流行歌手的首演
It's pointless division. You're not going to throw away your company chance
而放弃进军舞团的机会
to be the opening act of some pop star.
哀求她 奥利 四肢跪地
Beg for it, Ollie hands and knees.
你真是个有天赋的演员
You're a very talented performer,
你能让我表现更优秀
and you make me better than I am.
那你会帮我破解瑞贝卡之谜吗
Will you help me crack the Rebecca enigma?
你想干嘛
What do you want?
- 你忙着呢 - 我失业了 时间充沛得很
- You're busy. - I'm unemployed. I've got all the time in the world.
我听到了流言 但是
I heard a rumour, but...
官方说法是 我不适合新舞团
The official line is that I'm not a good fit for the new company.
实际上是瑞贝卡迫不及待把杰弗里先生的宠信们清理出局
But really Rebecca couldn't wait to purge Sir Jeffery's favourites.
我替你感到难过
I'm so sorry.
董事会还知道我是张王牌 我会与之斗争的
The board still knows I'm a draw card. I'm going to fight this.
那你需要些什么
So what do you need?
我得到了火鸟的角色 作为我的舞团试演片段
I've been given Firebird as my company audition piece.
你跳得比谁都好
And You dance it better than anyone
而且你也清楚如何避免受伤
and know how to work around an injury.
我在想或许你能帮我
I was wondering if maybe you'd help me...
作弊么
Cheat?
我在想要不要把后雀跃换成
I was thinking of changing the cabriole derriere
后背姿势更优美的动作 比如巴斯克舞步
to something more back-friendly like a saut de basque.
要是你试试做比如伸展双臂这样的动作
If you do things like extend the phrasing of the releves,
没人会注意到你的阿拉贝斯克姿势过低
no-one is going to care that the arabesque is lower.
你有考虑过强度低一些的独舞吗
Have you considered doing a solo that's less intense?
三年来我每周都跳六十小时
I've been dancing 60 hours a week for three years.
我要高强度而又戏剧性
I want to be intense and dramatic.
可是从长远角度来看呢
What about the long term though?
你逼迫自己忍受疼痛
You push yourself through the pain barrier
日复一日 年复一年
day after day, year after year...
相信我 我可不推崇这么做
Trust me, I don't recommend it.
- 要是你不想帮我 - 听着
- If you don't want to help... - Listen.
有个跟我同龄的女孩试镜跳了波尔赛弗涅
A girl in my year did Persephone for her audition.
我早就知道波尔赛弗涅了
I already know Persephone.
我来学院之前就跳过了 太简单
I did it before I came to the academy. It's too easy.
从技巧来看 是的
Technically, yes,
但是从艺术角度来看 你可以自由发挥
but artistically you could make it whatever you want.
如果你非要跳火鸟
If you persist with Firebird,
我帮不了你 我也不会帮你
I can't help you. I won't help you.
显然她的下一个电影
So obviously a stunt
就只能靠舞蹈特技了
to cash in on her next straight-to-Netflix movie.
雷恩老师 璐璐既然扮演我最好的朋友
Miss Raine, as Lulu is playing my best friend,
能不能麻烦你告诉她入戏点
could you tell her to get in character?
凯特莉娜 你重心不稳
Katrina You're tottering.
痛得好爽 真舒服
Oh! Good pain, good pain!
关于恶作剧日
So, Muck Up Day.
还记得去年怎么恶搞我那群敬爱的同班同学的吗
Remember last year's war against my esteemed classmates?
- 当然 - 想必你有什么敢想却不敢做的
- Of course. - Presumably you had battle plans
作战计划咯
that were never enacted.
暴打他们一顿
Dust them off.
瑞贝卡说他们需要的是全世界最出色的舞者
Rebecca said they're looking for the best dancers on the planet.
潜台词就是她要对学院不忠
Subtext - she has no loyalty to the academy,
这说得通 因为她从来就没对学院忠诚过
which makes sense, 'cause she never got in.
- 我们等会儿再说她 你只要闭嘴 漂漂亮亮的就好 - 真粗鲁
- We'll get to Rebecca later. Just shut up and look pretty. - Rude!
# 你自以为无所不知 你自以为无所不晓 #
You think you've got it, boy You think you know it all
# 世界如此之大 如此邪恶 #
This world is big and bad
# 谁都难料未来怎样 #
You don't know what it's got in store
# 激烈斗争吧 正如你遇见我 #
Got to fight so hard like you see me
# 就从今晚开始 #
And it's starting tonight
# 把音量调高 让音响爆破 #
So turn it up Let the speakers blow
# 熊熊燃烧吧 点燃小宇宙 #
Burn it up We can make fire
# 把音量调高 让音响爆破 #
Turn it up Let the speakers blow
# 每人都知道奥利无敌 #
Everybody know Ollie got the flow
# 今夜属于我 无处可逃 #
I own the night There's nowhere to run
# 无处可逃 #
And nowhere to hide
# 准备充分 #
I'm ready
# 没人能打倒我 #
No-one can't bring me down
# 我头戴皇冠 我是最棒的 #
I will hold the crown for the best around
# 躺在地板上 再给我更多 #
So let's take it to the floor Girl, give me more
# 我势不可挡 #
Ain't nobody going to stop me No
# 你无法阻止我 你无法阻止我 #
You can't stop me now You can't stop me now
# 我要打败你 #
I'm going to hold you down
# 你无法阻止我 你无法阻止我 #
You can't stop me now You can't stop me now
# 你无法阻止我 #
You can't stop me now
# 我要打败你 #
I'm going to hold you down
#　你无法阻止我 #
You can't stop me now.
我正抱着杰西卡・麦尔白呢
I'm supporting Jessica Mauboy!
今年真难熬 这是我首次胜利
It's been such a tough year. This is the first win I've had.
阿比盖尔 我们还未谋面呢
Abigail, we really didn't meet yet.
太惊艳了
So amazing.
- 我们会找个优秀的替代者 - 什么
- We'll find a great replacement. - Sorry?
大约六个人 站满整个舞台
Maybe half a dozen. Fill out the stage.
但你们是双人表演啊
But you're a duo.
不是 我是独唱
No, I'm a solo artist,
再说阿比盖尔已经忙于另一场试镜了
and Abigail is already tied up to another audition process.
我们就要这个组合
We want this.
就这个
Just this.
感觉怎么样
How is it feeling?
还好 就是独奏部分太简单了
Fine. It's just, the solo is too straightforward.
没办法通过它到达...
There's nothing to push through to get to...
哪里
Where?
我称它为神奇的地方
I call it, my magic place.
你知道的...就是一切突然间起作用的所在
You must know...where everything suddenly works.
灯光暗下去 只剩我和音乐
The lights fade and it's just me and the music.
塔拉 凭经验而言 这种时刻不可靠
Tara, speaking from experience, those moments can be unreliable.
这就是我为什么喜欢跳舞
They're also why I love dancing.
这很奇妙 喜欢归喜欢
That's fantastic. Love it all you like,
但是作为专业舞者 得看你在最糟糕的时刻如何应对
but being a professional is about what you do on your worst night,
如果在你的第一百场演出上
when it's your hundredth performance,
乐队演奏的太快了
the orchestra is playing too fast,
你的演出服掉了
your costume falls off.
你不能停下来告诉观众说
You can't just stop and turn to the audience and say,
对不起...奇迹没有发生
"Sorry...no magic."
那怎么办 就那么敷衍过去
So, what, you just fake it?
不是敷衍 你得相信自己已经做足了功课
No. You trust that you've done your homework,
每一个动作你都烂熟于心
that you've crafted your performance
而且让你的每一个舞步充满意义
and infused meaning into every step.
这才是成人的做法
That's how the grown-ups do it.
也就是说你清醒过来咯
Does this mean you've found the head space?
你在哪儿
Where are you?
你在当救生员
You're a lifeguard?
是的 我正在培训中
I'm in training to be one, yes.
没安排不代表做错了
Just because you didn't organise it doesn't make it wrong.
你不是说要进舞团吗
What happened to your speech about getting into the company?
你是真想加入 还是只不过做做样子
Did you want to get in or did you just say that for effect?
- 我百分之九十真想加入 - 克里斯提
- I'm 90% sure I want to. - Christian!
如果我没能如愿 我需要钱作为缓冲
If I don't get in, I'll need some cash as a buffer.
我快下班了
My shift is almost over.
你何不帮我改进一下救生技能呢
Why don't you help me with some rescue skills?
也许我们需要设置话题禁区
Maybe we need conversation embargoes,
不谈敏感话题
dangerous subjects we put into the no-fly zone.
比如你的事业和我的期望
Like your career and my expectations?
你没有试着纠正我
You don't try and fix me.
你也没有回避话题 那你告诉我你是怎么想的
You don't retreat. You tell me what you're thinking.
现在
Like right now?
你想知道我怎么想的吗
You want to know what I'm thinking?
神奇的时刻
Kind of a magic moment.
我听说这不可靠
I hear those are unreliable.
合约上只有经济舱旅行
They've only contracted economy-class travel.
我们需要个代理人吗 你能别假装你在读吗
Think we need an agent? Can you stop pretending to read that?
现在我来了 你想让我怎么挖丑闻
I'm here now. How do you want to dig for dirt?
严格地说 这次巡演已经到手了
Strictly for argument's sake, this tour is a bird in the hand.
每晚要在成千上万的观众前表演
It's performing in front of thousands every night.
是个不错的工作
It's a career.
- 而舞团那边完全是个未知数 - 你是说...
- The company is a total unknown. - You're saying...
如果我们拒绝这个工作 瑞贝卡又不要咱
How stupid would we feel if we turned this offer down
那将是多么愚蠢的选择
and Rebecca takes none of us?
怎么了
What?
没事 我正准备和你说说我的独舞
Doesn't matter. I was going to tell you about my solo,
但我们应该把它列为禁区 我很焦虑
but we should put that on the banned list. I get anxious.
这太傻了
This is stupid.
我突然不知道怎么跟你说了
I suddenly don't know what to say to you.
我们有话题雷区
There are minefields.
我们真能遵守规则 不以争吵告终吗
Can we really do rules so we don't end up fighting?
嘿 过来
Hey, come here.
你有没有想过 如果事情进展顺利
Have you ever thought that if it was going to work...
现在就已经顺利发生了吗
It would have happened by now?
我们并不是没试过 试了好多次了
It's not like we haven't tried lots of times.
我紧紧抓着那些神奇的时刻不放手
I cling onto those magic moments,
而在剩下的时间里 我们都在争吵
then the rest of the time we just fight.
伤害对方 我知道
And hurt each other. I know.
所以你觉得...
So do you think it's...
结束了吗
Over?
你觉得呢
Do you?
我们能不能往回倒退五分钟
Can't we just rewind five minutes?
要是...
What if...
什么
What?
我觉得 我不会再像爱你那样
I don't think I'm ever going to love anyone
爱任何人了
the way I love you.
我禁不住被电影 书本 和芭蕾故事里的
I can't help feeling manipulated by all those love stories
所有那些爱情故事左右
in all those movies and books and ballets.
他们教给我们 如果你经受了足够的考验 到最后就会成功
They teach that if you suffer enough, it works out in the end.
我想我应该退休
I think I'm going to retire.
什么 这世界上任何舞团都会抢着要你的
What? Any company in the world would take you in an instant.
我厌倦了每天早晨喝咖啡和止痛药了
I'm sick of starting each morning with coffee and a painkiller.
我不想再这样逼自己了
I don't want to push myself so hard anymore.
波尔塞福涅...你要用每一个舞步来讲述这个故事
Anyway, Persephone... you need to tell the story with every step.
我猜关键词是爱情故事
I guess the key phrase is, love story.
我不能再活在奇迹 虚幻的世界里
I can't live in a magic, made-up world any longer.
是时候强迫自己活在当下
It's time to force myself to be present,
对待爱情像最好的舞蹈一样
treat love like the best dancing,
在简单中追求不费力 没有痛苦 和美丽
aim for effortless, pain-free, beautiful in its simplicity.
如果是拿着名单的杰弗里先生 我会说我愿意参加巡演
If it was Sir Jeffery with his list, I'd say we take the tour
但是是瑞贝卡 我们什么都难以预料
but with Rebecca we still don't know anything.
好吧 调查暂且不谈 你对瑞贝卡的直觉怎样
OK, research aside, what are your gut feelings about Rebecca?
我认为...
I think...
..我觉得她爱芭蕾胜于一切
..I think she loves ballet more than anything.
反面 不惜一切代价进军舞团
Tails, you risk everything on the company.
正面 参加和麦尔白的巡演
Heads, tour with Mauboy.
三局两胜
Best of three?
请井然有序地
Nice and orderly, please.
径直穿过紧急通道
Straight through the emergency exit.
伙计 我们该走了
Mate, we've got to go.
我知道我不值得这个角色 但是我要试演白马王子
I don't deserve it, but if I'm going to be Prince Charming,
就需要你的帮助
I'm going to need your help.
来吧 走
Come on. Let's go.
波尔塞福涅太乏味了
Persephone is far too prosaic.
我不认为 我会让它很独特的
I disagree. I'll make it special.
不 你要听从指示 别着急
No, you'll take the time as instructed,
然后跳我选的独舞
then do the solo I selected.
尊敬的雷恩老师 我不答应
Respectfully, I won't, Miss Raine.
我会继续和赛斯吉娅合作 从她那儿我学到很多
I'll keep working with Saskia. I'm learning a lot from her.
各位 恶作剧日快乐
Happy Muck Up Day, everyone.
凯特莉娜・卡拉马科夫 过来 就现在
Katrina Karamakov! Here, now!
这是我们最后的码头大战 三周后我们就要毕业了
This is our last wharf battle. We graduate in three weeks.
游戏开始了 塔拉・韦伯斯特 游戏开始了
Game on, Tara Webster. Game on.